<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Articles to bee inquired of, in the diocesan visitation of the most reuerend father in God, Toby by the prouidence of God L. Archbishop of Yorke, primate of England, and metropolitane begun and continued in the yeeres of our Lord God 1622, and 1623, and in the 17 yeere of His Graces translation.</title>
            <author>Church of England. Province of York. Archbishop (1606-1628 : Matthew)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1623</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 27 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A00269</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 10379.5</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S2654</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">24455781</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 24455781</idno>
            <idno type="VID">27686</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A00269)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 27686)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1851:9)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Articles to bee inquired of, in the diocesan visitation of the most reuerend father in God, Toby by the prouidence of God L. Archbishop of Yorke, primate of England, and metropolitane begun and continued in the yeeres of our Lord God 1622, and 1623, and in the 17 yeere of His Graces translation.</title>
                  <author>Church of England. Province of York. Archbishop (1606-1628 : Matthew)</author>
                  <author>Matthew, Tobias, 1546-1628.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[16] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by George Purslowe,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1623.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signatures: A-B⁴ (last leaf blank).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Church of England --  Pastoral letters and charges.</term>
               <term>Visitations, Ecclesiastical --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:27686:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>ARTICLES to bee inquired of, <hi>Jn the Dioceſan <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>iſitation, of the moſt</hi> Reuerend Father in GOD, <hi>Toby</hi> by the prouidence of GOD L. Arch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>biſhop of <hi>Yorke,</hi> Primate of <hi>England,</hi> and Metropolitane.</p>
            <p>Begun and continued in the yeeres <hi>of our</hi> LORD GOD 1622. <hi>and</hi> 1623. And in the 17. yeere of his Graces Tranſlation.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed by <hi>George Purſlowe.</hi> Anno 1623.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="oath">
            <pb facs="tcp:27686:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>The tenor of the Oath to be mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtred to the Churchwardens and <hi>Sworne-men.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>YOV and euery of you ſhall ſweare by Almighty God, that (all affection and reſpect ſet aſide) vpon due &amp; deliberate conſideration of theſe Articles giuen in charge, you ſhall make a true, full and particular anſwer in writing, to the ſame Articles and euery of them, preſenting all and ſinguler offences, and offenders therein mentioned: wherein you ſhall deale faithfully, and vprightly, as before God. So helpe you God in Ieſus Chriſt.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:27686:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>Articles to be inquired of, by the Church-wardens and Sworne-men in the ſaid viſitation of the Lord Archbiſhop of <hi>Yorke.</hi> Anno Dom. 1623.</head>
            <div type="articles_for_clergy">
               <head>For the Clergie.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>Nprimis,</hi> Whether your Parſon, Vicar, Curate, or Miniſter be a Preacher of Gods Word, and a maintainer and furtherer of Religion now eſtabliſhed by publike au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority within this Realme of <hi>England,</hi> or no?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>2</label>  Whether hee doe in his Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons, Lectures, &amp; other exerciſes, moue the people to ioyne with him in Prayer for the Kings Maieſtie, the Noble Prince <hi>Charles, Fredericke</hi> the Prince Elector Palatine, the Lady <hi>Eli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zabeth</hi> his wife, and their Royall iſſue; with addition of ſuch ſtile and title as of right doth appertaine to his Maieſtie, and whether any, ſince the 25. of September 1605. haue refuſed, or willingly omitted, or neglected ſo to doe?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>3</label> Whether he be a Preacher lawfully admitted, and by what authority? And whether your Miniſter or Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens haue, ſince the time aforeſaid, ſuffered any man to preach in your Church, but ſuch as haue firſt ſhewed their li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſes to preach, either from the Lord Archbiſhop of <hi>Yorke,</hi> or Biſhop of the Dioceſſe, where hee dwelleth, or one of the Vniuerſities, vnder their Seale?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>4</label>  Whether he be painfull &amp; diligent in preaching, as alſo in Catechizing the youth of your Pariſh, vpon Sun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dayes
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:27686:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
&amp; Holydaies, according to his Maieſties late directions in that behalfe ſignified and regiſtred in the Conſiſtory office at <hi>Yorke?</hi> And how many Sermons hath your Parſon, Vicar, or Miniſter preached in his owne Church within this yeere laſt paſt? And if he be not a Preacher, how many Sermons by his procurement or otherwiſe haue there been preached this laſt yeere, and by whom? And whether were they that prea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ched the ſame, licenced or no, and by whome?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>5</label>  Whether any lectures bee read, or Exerciſes vſed within your Pariſh, either publikely in the Church, or priuat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly in any houſe by any not licenſed as aforeſaid: or being li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenced, doe refuſe to conforme themſelues to the Lawes, Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinances, and Rites Eccleſiaſticall of the Church of <hi>England?</hi> And whether any ſuch ſo reading or exerciſing, doe teach or profeſſe any doctrine of Innouation, inclyning to Papiſtry, Browniſm, or any other Hereſie or Schiſmaticall error, whereby themſelues or others may be drawne from their true obedience in cauſes Eccleſiaſticall?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>6</label>  Whether your Miniſter not being a Preacher, doe euery Sunday, when there is no Sermon, reade ſome part of the Homilies ſet forth and appointed by publike authority?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>7</label>  Whether your Common Prayer and Sacraments be by your Miniſter in your Church or Chappell, diſtinctly and reuerently adminiſtred and read, as is preſcribed in or by the booke of Common Prayer, without any innouation or omiſsion, and at due and conuenient houres? And whether doth your Miniſter ſo celebrating the ſame, vſually weare the Surpleſſe whileſt hee is ſaying the publike Prayers, and mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtring the Sacraments? And if he be a graduate, whether doth he alſo vpon his Surpleſſe weare ſuch a Hood, as is agreeable to his degree, and ſuch decent apparell, as by the late Conſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutions are appointed?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>8</label>  Whether doth your Miniſter in the adminiſtra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the Sacrament of Baptiſme, vſe the ſigne of the Croſſe, according to the Booke of Common Prayer? And whether hath hee deferred or refuſed to baptize any Infant being in
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:27686:3"/>
danger of death, hauing notice of the weakneſſe thereof? And whether in his default hath any dyed without Baptiſme?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>9</label>  Whether hath your Parſon, Vicar or Curate ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted any to the holy Communion, or to be God-father or God-mother at Baptiſme, being a perſon exco<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>municate, any known or notorious offenders, any not inſtructed in the prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciples of Religion, or any to the Co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>munion which then were not of your Pariſh? And whether hath he ſo often and at ſuch times adminiſtred the ſame, as euery Pariſhioner may receiue the ſame at the leaſt euery yeere thrice, wherof once at Eaſter, as by the Booke of Common Prayer is appointed?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>10</label>  Whether hath he admitted any exco<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>municate perſon to be God-father or God-mother, or any which hath not receiued the holy Communion?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>11</label>  Whether hath he churched any woman after the birth of her child begotten in Inceſt, Adultery, Fornication, or married any woman ſo begotten with child, without publike confeſsion of their faults at their churching or marriages in the preſence of the Congregation, vpon ſome Sabbath or Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtiuall day at morning Prayer time, leauing their further pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment to the Ordinary, or other competent Iudge?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>12</label>  Whether hath your Parſon, Vicar, or Curate, ſince the 25. of Sept. 1605. celebrated Matrimony without licence granted by ſuch as haue Epiſcopal authority, except the banes of Matrimony were formerly publiſhed three Sundaies or ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lydayes in the time of diuine ſeruice, in the Pariſh Church or Chappell where the ſaid parties dwelt and at any other time then betweene the houres of eight and twelue of the clocke in the fore-noon, or in any other place, then in the Church or Chappell, where one of the parties dwelt? And whether without conſent of Parents, or other Gouernours?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>13</label>  Whether hath your Parſon, Vicar or Curate, moe Benefices or Eccleſiaſticall promotions then one, and what be their names, and where is he moſt reſiant? And if hee haue more, how is hee qualified and diſpenſed withall to hold the ſame? And how doth he ſupply his abſence, whether by a
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:27686:4"/>
Curate or Miniſter licenced to preach, or not? And if he bee, then by whom is hee licenced? And what diſtribution doth he make thereby to the poore, where he is not reſident?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>14</label>  Whether doth your Miniſter or Curate ſerue a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny more Cures then one; and if ſo, then what other Cure doth he ſerue?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>15</label>  Whether doth your Parſon, Vicar or Curate, according to an act of Parliament in that behalfe made, call vpon and require the people of his Pariſh to ſolemnize and keepe holy the Fift day of Nouember, and that day to come to the Church to ioyne in Prayers and thankſgiuing for the happy deliuerance of his Maieſty, the Queene, Prince, and States of Parliament from the moſt traiterous and bloudy in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended maſſare by Gunpowder? and whether doe the people of your pariſh accordingly repaire to the Church, or doe any refuſe or neglect ſo to do? preſent their names &amp; Sur-names.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>16</label>  Whether doth he carefully viſit the ſicke of his Pariſh, by exhorting and miniſtring vnto them, as by the Booke of Common Prayer is appointed. And whether doth he attend the buriall of the dead, by meeting the Corpes at the Church-ſtile, and ſo accompany the ſame to the Church or Graue, ſaying or ſinging ſuch places of Scripture as are appointed by the ſayd Booke?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>17</label>  Whether is your Miniſter ſuſpected or defamed to haue obtained his Benefice by Symonie, or reputed to bee an incontinent perſon, or keepeth any woman in his houſe ſuſpected of incontinency, or giuen to exceſsiue drinking; or a common gameſter or player at Dice, or doth keepe or ſuffer to be kept any Ale-houſe in his parſonage, or Vicarage-houſe, or faulty in any other crime puniſhable by the Eccleſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>aſticall cenſures, whereby he is offenſiue to his Miniſterie and calling?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>18</label>  Whether your Miniſter, Church-wardens and others, for the retaining of the circuit of your Pariſh by per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ambulations, as hath been preſcribed, doe vſe the ſame with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out ſuperſtition, or popiſh Ceremonie?</p>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:27686:4"/>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>19</label> Whether doth your Parſon or Vicar maintaine and keepe in due reparations the manſion-houſes and other Edifices belonging to their Eccleſiaſticall liuings, without ſuffering them to fall into ruine and decay?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>20</label>  Whether doth your Miniſter euery Sunday, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Booke of Common Prayer, make knowne to the people what Holydayes and faſting dayes are in the week following?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>21</label>  Whether doth your Miniſter being a Preacher, offer quiet and temperate conference to Popiſh Recuſants: and endeuour diligently to reclaime them from their errors? And whether they or any of them refuſe ſuch conference of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered vnto them by your ſaid Miniſter, or other Preacher, and what be their names and ſurnames?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>22</label>  Whether any Biſhop, Chancellor, Arch-deacon, Commiſſary, Officiall, or other Iudge or Officer Eccleſiaſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>call, for any compoſition, agreement or payment of any ſum of money, haue ſuppreſſed and concealed the excommunica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion or other Eccleſiaſticall cenſure, of or againſt any Popiſh recuſant or other offender? And what ſumme of money or other conſideration hath beene promiſed or receiued in that behalfe to your knowledge, or as you haue heard reported?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>23</label>  Whether doth your Miniſter euery halfe yeere once denounce in your Pariſh, all ſuch Pariſhioners as doe re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maine excommunicate and ſeeke not to bee abſolued? And how long hath any excommunicate perſon continued vnder the cenſure thereof, and admitted into the Church without a Certificate of his abſolution from the Ordinary?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>24</label>  Whether hath your Miniſter publikely in your Pariſh Church or Chappell once euery yeere read ouer the Conſtitutions and Canons Eccleſiaſticall, agreed vpon by the Clergie of both Prouinces, <hi>Anno Domini</hi> 1603. according to his Maieſties commandement?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="articles_for_laymen">
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:27686:5"/>
               <head>For the Laity.</head>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">ITem </seg>25</label>  Whether you haue in your Pariſh Church or Chappell all things neceſſary and requiſite for Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Prayer, and adminiſtration of the Sacraments: As the Booke of Common Prayer with the new Kalender: The Engliſh Bible of the new Tranſlation in the largeſt volume: Two Pſalters: Two bookes of Homilies: A decent Bapti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtery or Font: A Table of the 10. Commandements: A con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uenient ſeat for the Miniſter to read ſeruice in: A comely and decent Pulpit with Cloth and Cuſhion for the ſame: A come<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Communion Table, with a faire linnen cloth to lay vpon the ſame, and ſome couering of ſilke, or other decent ſtuffe for the cleane keeping thereof: A fayre and comely Communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on cup of ſiluer, with a ſiluer couer, ſuch as may ſerue for mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſtration of the holy Communion: A decent large Surpleſſe with ſleeues: A Cheſt or box for the poore: And the ſayd booke of Conſtitutions and Canons Eccleſiaſticall?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>26</label>  Whether the body of your Church and Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pell, with the Chancell be well and ſufficiently repaired, and kept without prophanation or abuſe any way? And if decay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed or prophaned, through whoſe default? And whether your bels and ſtals in the ſame be well maintained, your Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yard wel walled or fenced, and decently kept? and if the ſame in any part be decayed, through whoſe default?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>27</label>  Whether any Almes-houſe, Hoſpitall, Schoole or Spittell within your Pariſh be well and godly vſed, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the foundation and true intent of the Founders there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of? And whether any penſion or ſtipend due to any of them be detained, and by whome?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>28</label>  Whether the Baptiſtery or Font bee remoued from the vſuall place; or whether any perſons leauing the vſe thereof, doe baptize children in baſons or other veſſels not vſed in the Church, or whether any children be baptized or chriſtened in priuate houſes, otherwiſe then in caſes of neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſity,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:27686:5"/>
and by a lawfull Miniſter: and if yea, then whoſe chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren were they, and by whom were they baptized? And whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ſuch ſo baptized, were afterwards brought to the Church for further manifeſtation and approbation thereof, according to the Booke of Common Prayer?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>29</label>  Whether are there any perſon or perſons inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting or ſoiourning within your Pariſh or Chappelrie, that be notorious Recuſants, or which negligently or ſeldome come to your Church or Chappell, vpon Sabbaths or Feſtiual daies, and who be they, and what be their names and ſurnames, and with who<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> haue they ſoiourned, &amp; how long haue they ſo con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinued, &amp; of what eſtate, age, condition or degree they are of, &amp; whether there be any within your ſaid pariſh or chappelry, aboue the age of 16. yeeres which doe not yeerely communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate thriſe at the leaſt, wherof once at Eaſter, &amp; who be they?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>30</label>  Whether are there any reſiant within our pariſh, who haue beene conuicted of Recuſancie, which haue confor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med themſelues, &amp; not receiued the Sacrament of the Lords Supper within one whole yeere after the conformitie, and for how many yeeres haue they not receiued the ſame, and what be their names and ſurnames?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>31</label>  Whether are there within your pariſh any Popiſh Recuſants, of bold, inſolent, &amp; offenſiue behauiour, which pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſume to ſeduce and withdraw others, either in or of their owne families or elſewhere, from the true Religion now eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſhed, or from due obedience to his Maieſtie; or which make ſpeciall choiſe of Recuſants to be their ſeruants?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>32</label>  Whether doe your Miniſter, Church-wardens, Queſt-men and Aſsiſtants yeerely within fortie daies after Eaſter exhibite to the Biſhop or his Chancellour, according to the 112. Canon, the names and ſurnames of all the Pariſhio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners as well men as women, which being of the age of 16. yeeres, receiued not the Communion at Eaſter before.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>33</label>  Whether the youth of your pariſh do diligently re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paire to your Church or Chappell vpon Sabbaths, and Holy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daies to be Catechized. And if not in whoſe default, Cano<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> 59.</p>
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:27686:6"/>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>34</label> Whether any doe go out of the Church or Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pell, or doe vſe talking, walking, or ſleeping, or any other vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeemely offence, or other vnreuerend behauiour in the time of publike Prayer, Preaching, celebration of the Sacrament, or catechizing? and who are they?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>35</label>  Whether there bee any which priuately or pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>likely by ſpeech, or otherwiſe depraue any part of the true Religion eſtabliſhed within this Realme, or the Miniſters or Profeſſors thereof: or whether any Lectures, conuenticles, or priuate exerciſes be read or vſed within your Pariſh either in the Church, or in any houſe? And whether any ſuch Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der doe teach any doctrine of Innouation, to with-draw the people from their due obedience to the ordinances of the Church ſet forth by publike authoritie, or to cauſe them to forbeare to participate in Prayers, or Sacraments with our Church?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>36</label>  Whether haue you any Schoole-maſter, who teacheth either publikely or priuately within your ſaid Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh or Chappelrie, not being lawfully licenſed thereunto by writing vnder ſeale, and how long hath he there taught? And whether doth he teach the Booke intituled, <hi>God and the King,</hi> according to his Maieſties Proclamation?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>37</label>  Whether any within your Pariſh or Chappelry doe ſuffer to eat, drinke, play, iangle, or talke in their houſe or yard? Or any Butcher or Tradeſ-man their ſhop-windowes to be kept open to ſell meate, drinke, or wares on Sundaies in time of morning and euening Prayers, Sermons, Lectures, or Catechizing: or any that labour or worke on the Sabbaths, or other commanded Feſtiuall daies, to the hinderance of Prayers, Sermons, or other godly exerciſes?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>38</label>  Whether any within your Pariſh doe chide, brawle, quarrell, or fight within your Church or Church-yard, what are their names and ſurnames, and who bee the ſame? And whether any of them haue drawne any weapon there, with purpoſe to ſtrike with the ſame?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>39</label>  Whether are there within your ſaid pariſh or
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:27686:6"/>
chappelrie, any Ruſh-bearing, Bull-baitings, Beare-baitings, May-games, Morice-dances Ailes, or any ſuch like prophane paſtimes or aſſemblies on the Sabbath, to the hinderance of Prayers, Sermons, or other go<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ly exerciſes?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>40</label>  Whether there be any within your pariſh of tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bulent conuerſation behauing themſelues rudely or diſorder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly in your Church or Chappell, or which by vntimely ringing of Bells, by walking, talking, or otherwiſe haue hindered the Miniſter or Preacher?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>41</label>  Whether bee there any within your pariſh or chappelrie, that vſe to ring the Bells ſuperſtitiouſly vpon any abrogated Holy-daies, or the Eauens thereof? And whether is the Paſsing Bell tolled when any Chriſtian bodie is ſicke and like to die, as it ought to be? And after the death of any, whether there be any ſuperſtitious ringing, ſuperſtitious bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning of candles ouer the corſe in the day time, after it bee light: Or praying for the dead at croſſes, or places where croſſes haue beene, in the way to the Church, or any other ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perſtitious vſe of croſſes, with towels, palmes metwands, or other memories of Idolatries at burialls, or ſuperſtitiouſly doe goe on Pilgrimages, or any places dedicated to our Lady, or any Saints, or otherwiſe?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>42</label>  Whether are you prouided of a Parchment Booke, in which haue beene and are written the names of all children, men, and women baptized, married, or buried with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in your pariſh contained in your former Regiſter Booke, and ſince the beginning of the Reigne of the late Queene <hi>Eliza<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beth?</hi> And whether the day and yeere of euery chriſtning, wedding, and buriall, which haue beene in your pariſh, hath beene duely written in the booke? And whether you haue a ſure coffer, with three lockes and keyes for the ſafe cuſtodie thereof? And whether are the names of all ſuch ſo chriſtned, married, or buried, tranſmitted yeerely within this Dioceſſe, to the Lord Arch-biſhop or his Chancellor, to be preſerued in the Regiſtrie of the ſaid Lord Arch-biſhop, according to the ſeuentieth Canon and Conſtitution Eccleſiaſticall?</p>
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:27686:7"/>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>43</label> Whether is there placed by your Regiſter, two ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, containing the ſeuerall rates and ſums of all fees due to the Iudge and other Officers of your Court, one in the vſual place or Conſiſtorie where the Court is kept, and the other in his Regeſtrie in ſuch ſort, as euery man may come to view the ſame without difficultie? And whether your Chancellour, Arch-deacon, or any other Officer or Miniſter, doe exact or extort any greater fees or ſums of money, then in the ſaid Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles are contained and if ſo, let the ſame be expreſſed?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>44</label>  Whether are there, or haue beene ſince his Maie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties moſt happy reigne ouer this Kingdome, within your Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh or Chappelrie any inceſtuous perſons, adulterers or for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nicators? Or ſince the 25. of <hi>September</hi> 1605. any Vſurers, Drunkards, Swearers, or any other who are vehemently ſuſpected or defamed of any ſuch crime, and who be they?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>45</label>  Whether within your Pariſh or Chappelrie are there, or haue beene ſince his Maieſties ſo happie reigne, any perſons hauing two wiues, or any women two husbands, or any married within the degrees forbidden, or without Banes three ſeuerall Sundayes or Holidaies firſt publiſhed, without lawfull licence thereunto by ſuch as haue Epiſcopall autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritie, or any who haue had carnall knowledge together be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore their marriage, or that are vehemently ſuſpected thereof, and who they be?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtē, </seg>46</label> Whether any within your Pariſh or Chappelry, not being licenced or diſpenced withall, as aforeſaid, haue beene married within the time by law prohibited, that is to ſay, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tweene Aduent Sunday, and the 13. day of <hi>Ianuary,</hi> being <hi>Hillarie</hi> day, or betweene <hi>Septuageſima</hi> Sunday, and the Sun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day next after Eaſter, or betweene the Sunday next before the Aſcenſion day, and Trinitie Sunday next enſuing? let their names be expreſſed, as well of the Miniſter ſo marrying any, as of the parties ſo married.</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>47</label>  Whether haue any beene priuately married to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether within your Pariſh, by any vnknowne Prieſt or Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter, or any who haue not procured their children to bee pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>likely
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:27686:7"/>
baptized in your ſaid Church or Chappel, according to Booke of Common Prayer, and who they be?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>48</label>  Whether any within your Pariſh or Chappelry haue harboured any women begotten with child forth of lawfull Matrimony, &amp; haue ſuffered them to depart away vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puniſhed? Or any who do harbor or relieue any obſtinate Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſants or excommunicated perſons, and what, and how ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Recuſants or perſons excommunicate bee there within your ſaid Pariſh or Chappelrie, and how long haue they ſo re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mained, and for what cauſes they were ſo excommunicate?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>49</label>  Whether any of your Pariſh doe refuſe to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tribute towards the reparations of your Church or Chappel, or towards the prouiſion of any neceſſary ornaments therein, or that refuſe to pay your Curate or Pariſh Clerke his wages, or other vſuall duties, and who they be?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>50</label>  Whether the Church-wardens and Side-men be choſen according to the 89. and 90. Canons; and during their time, haue faithfully and dutifully diſcharged their office, and at or before their going out of the ſame, made a iuſt account of their receits and proceedings to the vſe of the Church? And whether any part of your Church ſtocke, or any other thing giuen to any godly publike vſe be deliuered to any, or otherwiſe imployed, then appertaineth?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>51</label>  Whether your Pariſh Clerke be dutifull and dili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent in attending the Miniſter, and of ſufficiency to diſcharge his place or not?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>52</label>  Whether any within your Pariſh or Chappelrie, doe occupy or intermeddle with the goods or cattels of any deceaſed perſon whatſoeuer, whoſe wil, if any ſuch be not law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully approued, or dying Inteſtate, the Adminiſtration thereof not lawfully granted, and who they be?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>53</label>  Whether your Arch-deacon, his Officiall or Depie, or any other exerciſing Eccleſiaſticall Iuriſdiction, within this Dioceſſe in places exempt or not exempt, other then the Chancellor of the ſaid Dioceſſe, eſpecially ſince the 25. of <hi>September</hi> 1605. haue taken vpon them to grant any
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:27686:8"/>
licence for marriages within your pariſh? And how many li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſes haue beene ſo granted, and what be the names of them that haue beene married by vertue of any ſuch licence, and by what Miniſter haue the ſame beene celebrated?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>54</label>  Whether the ſaid Arch-deacon or others, as aforeſaid, haue ſince the 25. day of <hi>September</hi> 1605. cenſured, or abſolued any perſon or perſons, which haue by law incur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red the ſentence of Excommunication <hi>ipſo facto,</hi> either for ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lemnizing or being preſent at any marriages, the banes not aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked, nor any lawfull licence obtained, or for fighting, quarrel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, or brawling, or drawing any weapon with purpoſe to ſtrike in any Church or Church-yard?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Item </seg>55</label>  Whether the ſaid Arch-deacon or others, as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, haue ſince the ſaid 25. day of <hi>September</hi> 1605. gran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted any admiſsions for Curates, licences for Schoole-maſters or Pariſh Clerkes, ſequeſtrations of vacant Benefices, by their ſuppoſed authoritie, and how many, and to whom, and what be their names?</p>
               <p>
                  <label type="milestone">
                     <seg type="milestoneunit">Jtem </seg>56</label>  Whether haue they, or any of them, commuted any corporall puniſhment for any ſum of money, and what be their names whoſe puniſhment haue beene commuted, for what offence, by whom, and for what ſumme of money, and how hath the ſaid money beene imployed?</p>
               <p>
                  <milestone type="tcpmilestone" unit="unspecified" n="57"/> And laſtly, Whether is there within your ſaid Pariſh or Chappelrie, any offendour or offendours in any other crime againſt the ſaid Canons and Conſtitutions, and other Lawes Eccleſiaſticall, not expreſly contained in any of theſe Articles, whoſe reformation may bee had by Eccleſiaſticall authoritie, and who, and what the ſame are?</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:27686:8"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
